Are you all right to grab the back end?
-准备好抓住蛇的尾巴了吗？
Uh, well, not at the moment.
-呃 还没
Not yet.
-不是现在
Get him up.
抓紧它
You gotta lock him in.
你得把它锁在里面
A scratch from this species will knock you.
这些蛇的咬伤能让你倒下
Knock you down...
-倒下...
Could kill you? Or...
致命吗
Oh definitely, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 那当然
Okay.
-行
So I am back in Australia,
我又回到了澳大利亚
and, of course, I'm a reminded
我牢记着这个国家有太多致命的生物
that everything in this country is trying to kill you,
particularly snakes and spiders,
特别是蛇和蜘蛛
and here at the Australian Reptile Park
而在澳大利亚爬行动物公园这里
they actually milk snakes and spiders
他们居然在挤蛇和蜘蛛的毒液
so they can use their venom to make antivenom
用来制作抗毒血清  拯救人的生命
and save lives.
Let's go see how they do it.
看看他们是怎样制作的
All right, so come on in, man.
-进来吧  伙计
This is without a doubt
毋庸置疑
the most dangerous room in the country.
这是澳大利亚最危险的房间
You're currently surrounded floor to ceiling with venomous snakes.
你现在从头到脚都被毒蛇包围了
And the only thing that keeps the snakes in
-而唯一能阻止蛇出来的
is those little locks?
是那些小锁？
Yeah, just the little locks and the thin glass.
-嗯，只有小锁和薄薄一层玻璃
Did a snake actually do that?
-那裂痕真是蛇撞的吗？
Yeah.
-是的
So a kid was tapping on the glass.
有个孩子在敲打玻璃
I told him not to,
我叫他不要这样做
his parents are like nah, it's all good.
他的父母说 这能有啥事
And I'm like, don't tap on the glass, man.
我就说 别敲玻璃了伙计
The snake goes, (thumps fist)
这时蛇窜了出来  *撞击声*
The kid ran out with the smelling of a crap, so yeah.
那孩子跑了出来  吓得屁滚尿流
For real? - Yeah, oh yeah.
-真的吗？ -是的
He went (mimics a kid screaming)
那孩子  *模仿孩子的尖叫*
He went screaming out the room.
那孩子尖叫着冲出房间
In Australia we lose one to three people per annum to snake bite.
在澳大利亚 每年都会有1至3个人死于蛇咬伤
aaaaa
ooooo ooooo ooooo
ooooo ooooo
Internationally estimates by the World Health Organization
而世卫组织估计  全球每年死于蛇咬的人数
aaaaa
ooooo ooooo ooooo
ooooo ooooo
aaaaa
ooooo ooooo ooooo
ooooo ooooo
is 120,000.
达到了12万
So not only do we have some of the best
因此 我们不仅有世界顶级的抗毒血清产品
antivenom products anywhere on the planet,
but we have a federally funded antivenom program,
还有个抗毒血清项目得到了联邦资助
which means no matter who you are,
意味着  任何人都能免费获得抗蛇毒血清
you get antivenom for free.
So we'll probably play with a big coastal taipan
我们先玩玩一条大的“海岸太攀蛇”
to start with.
Yeah.
-是的
So why are we starting big?
所以为什么我们要从大的开始？
Oh we may as well. (Derek laughs)
-哦 我们也可以这样
You tell me what I need to do.
-你告诉我我需要做什么
Righty-O
好
I'm just gonna grab a vial from behind you
我只是要从你后面拿一个小瓶
'cause obviously we use
在我们这里
only the most highly scientific pieces of equipment here
最高科技的科学设备就是这瓶子了
at the Reptile Park.
Got it.
-明白了
It's our shot glass.
- 是我们的小酒杯
- Beautiful.
- 好极了
And I might even get you to hold that for me
- 请你帮我拿着这个
Great.       - For a second.
- 好的       - 就一小会
This is one of our big boys.
它是我们这儿的大宝贝
Hopefully he's in a good mood.
希望他现在心情不错
As you can see, quite a large individual.
看到了吧  好大一只
Now what we're gonna do.
接下来我们要做的
Is pin him.
是把它按住
Now, wait, wait, wait.
现在 等着
Get him up.
-抓紧它
Righty-O
对  就这样握住尾巴
There you go, you hold that,
I'll take that vial off you.
我来拿瓶子
This feels absurd.
这看上去很离谱
There we go.
-我们开始吧
As you can see, he's keen on the killing.
正如你所看到的 它热衷于杀戮
Now snakes aren't stupid.
这条蛇可不笨
He doesn't wanna bite the jar,
它不想咬这个玻璃罐
he wants to bite me.
它想咬我
Finger is the target.
我的手指是它的目标
There we go.
开始了
Oh my goodness.
我的天
That was a lot of venom delivered very quickly.
好多毒液迅速地射了出来
Yeah, they're not mucking around.
对 它们不是在搞笑
Now what we'll do is we'll actually give his venom glands
现在准备给它的毒腺做一点儿按摩
a little bit of a massage.
So what you would consider his cheeks,
所以你会考虑它的脸颊
give them a little bit of a roll,
稍微揉上两下
see if we can get an extra drop or two
看看能不能再挤出一两滴毒液
'cause every drop matters.
因为每滴都很重要
Now, because my hand's starting to cramp up,
-我的手开始抽筋了
I'm gonna put him away.
得把它关回去
So I'll get you guys to jump back for me.
你可以退两步腾点地方吗
And this is the sketchy bit.
下一步就很简单了
Yeah.
-恩
When you get him out, you got the hook,
弄它出来时能用钩子
when you're putting him back,
可是把它放回去的时候
it's just who's quicker.
就是看谁更快了
Ready?
预备
Two.
二
Are your hands trembling a little bit?
- 手发抖了？
Yeah, every time.
- 嗯，每次都是
So how much venom do you actually need
那制作抗毒血清究竟需要多少毒液呢？
to make antivenom?
About 15.
-大概15条蛇的
15 snakes to make one vial of antivenom?
一小瓶抗毒血清用15条蛇的毒液制造？
Yeah.
-是的
Venom evolved from saliva
毒液是由唾液进化而来的
and it's used primarily for catching and digesting prey.
主要用来捕捉和消化猎物
Each species of snake has a different venom
每种蛇的毒液都不同
tailored to the specific animals they hunt.
都是为它们的猎物量身定制的
The venom was originally squirted
最初的时候
into a snake's mouth by the back teeth,
毒液由蛇的后牙喷入蛇口
and to this day,
如今
almost 2/3 of all snakes are rear fanged.
差不多2/3的蛇  毒牙都在后方
Now why the rear tooth, you might ask?
所以你可能会问  为啥是后牙嘞
Well, it's because the venom gland itself
因为蛇的毒腺实际上长在眼睛后面
is actually behind the snake's eye.
So the shortest distance for a duct
所以对于毒液导管来说
is directly downwards to the back end of the top jaw.
最短距离就是直接向下延伸到上颚的后端
In some species,
对于某些品种
evolutionary pressures caused the fangs to move closer
进化的压力迫使毒牙前移
and closer to the front of the jaw,
逐渐靠近上颚的前端
improving the snake's ability to catch and kill prey.
这提高了蛇捕捉和击杀猎物的能力
While the location of the fangs was evolving,
在毒牙位置发生改变的同时
so were the fangs themselves.
毒牙本身也在进化
They started off as smooth ordinary teeth
毒牙最初只是光滑的普通牙齿
with venom flowing down the outside,
毒液顺着毒牙的表面流下来
but over time,
但时过境迁
some snake lineages evolved a groove in each fang
有些蛇的毒牙  进化出了一个凹槽
to channel the flow of venom.
用来为毒液导流
In some species, the groove became deeper and deeper
某些物种的蛇  凹槽变得越来越深
eventually closing in to form a hollow tube,
最终闭合成了中空的导管
and now the teeth literally inject venom into prey.
所以实际上  毒牙是将毒液“注射”到猎物的体内
But this is not the norm.
这并不是普遍现象
Only 1/7 of the world's snakes have hollow fangs,
全球范围内只有1/7的蛇拥有中空的毒牙
but, of course, almost all the venomous snakes in Australia
当然 澳洲的几乎所有毒蛇
do have hollow fangs,
都有这种高级毒牙
so we set up this macro shot to take a closer look.
所以我们安排了微距镜头  给它来个近距离特写
This one's rolling.
这边好了
That one's rolling.
那边也好了
We're ready when you're.
你们好了我们就开始
We're ready.
我们好了
Perfect.
完美
All right, everyone's ready?
那么  都准备好了吗
Wow.
哇哦
It's got like jets
就像个喷嘴一样
Jets of venom coming out.
这喷涌而出的毒液啊
Has this guy not been milked in a while or?
这家伙多久没挤毒液了
Yeah, it's been a little while.
是啊  有点久了
Not only do we have some of the most toxic snakes on the planet here,
我们这儿不仅有全地表毒性最强的蛇
we also selectively breed them
为了制造抗蛇毒血清
for the production of antivenom.
还对它们进行了选择性育种
They're bred to produce more venom
使得它们能产生的毒液比野生同类更多
than their wild counterparts.
So some of our coastal taipans are producing five, six
所以我们这儿培育的太攀蛇
nearly seven times what their wild counterpart would,
毒液产量是野生同类的五  六  甚至七倍
and that's just from selective breeding.
这正是选择性育种的结果
You find your two most psychotic ones,
选出两个最疯的
you put them together,
让它俩繁殖
you hope for the best and the absolute worst comes out.
你抱着最好的期望  然而绝对会出现最坏的结果
So keeps you on your toes.
所以  别高兴得太早
That sounds horrendous.
听起来好嚇人
So you're saying that
所以说
these are the most venomous snakes in the world,
这儿本就有地球上最毒的蛇
and then you have bred them to be more venomous?
你还把它们培育得更毒了
Yeah, they're super snakes.
没错  它们是超级毒蛇
A scratch from any of these animals could kill you.
被这些动物随便划一下就会寄
And some of these snakes are giving 4.5,
这里有的蛇 一口能喷 4.5
4.9 grams of venom per bite,
4.9 克的毒液
which is just stupid amounts.
量大得惊人
We spoke to venom expert, Timothy Jackson
我们与毒液专家  蒂莫西·杰克森进行了谈话
who argued these snakes produce more venom
他提出质疑说 这些蛇能生产更多的毒液
because they are regularly milked, unlike wild snakes.
是因为它们经常被挤毒液  而野生蛇不会这样
Either way, the snakes in this room contain more venom
无论如何  这房间里的蛇
than virtually any others on earth.
几乎拥有全地表最高的毒液产能
We house the second, the third, the fourth, the fifth,
我们这儿有毒蛇排行榜中第二到第五
and about the 12th or 13th most toxic,
和大概第十二或者第十三的蛇
depending on who you talk to.
得看你跟谁比了
One bite from a King Cobra
眼镜王蛇的一口毒液
contains enough venom to kill 13,000 mice,
足以杀死13000只老鼠
and we know this because of a study from 1979
这得从1979年的一个研究说起
that tested the venoms of 25 different species of snake
研究者取了25条不同种类蛇的毒液
on lab mice.
在小白鼠身上测量
From this, we can estimate
实验结果表明
that the venom from one King Cobra bite
眼镜王蛇的一口毒液
could kill around four humans,
差不多可以杀死四个人
though to be precise,
虽然准确来说
we'd have to say four human-sized rodents
是四个与人类同体积的啮齿动物
because thankfully, no one's tested these venoms on humans.
因为谢天谢地  没人真的在人身上做实验
And by this measure,
按照这样的算法
the most venomous snake in the world is the inland taipan,
世界上最毒的蛇是内陆太攀蛇
which conveniently lives in the middle of Australia.
它们生活在澳洲中部附近
A bite from the inland taipan
内陆太攀蛇的一口毒液
has enough venom to kill half a million mice,
足以杀死五十万只老鼠
or more than 100 humans.
或者说  一百多个人
So yeah, why not milk that one next?
那么  下一条不妨就是它了
So the next one, we're gonna step it up another notch.
接下来这条 我们要上点档次了
So this is the inland taipan,
这条就是内陆太攀蛇
also known as the fierce snake,
也被称为凶猛蛇
the most toxic land snake on the planet.
是地球上毒性最强的陆生蛇
These guys have the ability with one drop of venom
这些家伙只要一滴毒液
to knock over 100 adult humans.
就足以干掉 100 多位成年人
So stupidly toxic.
超级超级剧毒
So quite a lot smaller
它比我们刚才那几条小不少
than the last couple of animals we've used,
but makes up for it in toxicity.
但毒性弥补了这一点
Very, very quick and very naughty when he wants to be,
这家伙性情顽劣 动作迅猛
but an absolutely gorgeous pattern.
但也相当优雅
You can grab that bit for me, mate.
伙计 帮我抓住那里
Yes.
好
I'm gonna grab this vial from behind you.
我得拿上你身后这个小杯
And as you can see,
如你所见
he's very keen on the killing.
它相当热衷于杀戮
There we go.
开始了
That is extraordinary.
这真是非同寻常
The most venomous snake in the world.
世界上最毒的蛇
Just incredible animals, aren't they?
真是令人难以致信的生物 是吧？
(cage door shuts)
（关上笼门）
(laughs)
（笑声）
That was quick.
很快啊
Yeah, those ones make me proper nervous.
是啊 这真让我紧张
I don't know about you guys,
我不知道你们什么感觉
but I'm sweating.
但是我都冒冷汗了
Can you see the hands?
你知道你的手在抖吗？
The moment I stop doing that after a milking
如果哪天  我挤完后手不抖了
is the day I quit.
八成是我见阎王了
The concept of the most venomous snake is complicated
「最毒的蛇」的概念其实很复杂
because snakes evolved their venom specifically
因为蛇的毒液在进化过程中
for potency against their usual prey,
会特异性地增强对它们通常猎物的效力
in turn, their prey evolved resistance to their venom.
相应地 它们的猎物也会进化出抵抗力
The honey badger, for example,
例如蜜獾
is almost completely immune to Cobra venom.
几乎对眼镜蛇毒液完全免疫
So the lethality of a bite depends on the snake,
因此蛇咬伤的致命性既取决于蛇
the animal that got bitten,
也取决于被咬的动物
and the amount of venom injected.
还取决于注入了多少毒液
The reason scientists test different venoms on lab mice
科学家之所以要在小鼠上测试各种毒液
is to get an estimate of the amount of antivenom
是为了估计中和咬伤所需的血清用量
that would be required to neutralize a bite.
Snake venom is lethal to us
蛇毒对我们来说是致命的
because we are closely related to snakes' main prey,
因为人类的亲缘接近蛇类的主要猎物
rodents.
啮齿动物
Rodents and primates split on the evolutionary tree
啮齿动物和灵长动物进化上的分叉
only 75 million years ago,
距今仅 7500 万年
so we share a lot of the same biology,
因此我们有很多共同的生物学特征
from the structure of our cells to the way our blood clots,
从我们的细胞结构 到凝血方式
to how our nerves send signals.
再到神经信号的传递
Venoms typically target very conserved molecular pathways
毒液通常针对广泛保有的分子通路
that exist across maybe all vertebrates
这些通路几乎存在于所有脊椎动物中
or maybe even the entire tree of life in some cases.
有的甚至存在于几乎所有物种
There are four ways that snake venom can kill you.
蛇毒通常有四种方式杀死你
It can be neurotoxic,
它可能有神经毒性
damaging to your nervous system and brain
通过干扰神经递质
by interfering with neurotransmitters,
即神经元之间传递信号的化学物质
the signaling chemicals that go between neurons.
损伤你的大脑和神经系统
It can be hemotoxic,
它可能有血液毒性
thinning out your blood,
稀释你的血液
preventing wounds from healing
阻止伤口愈合
and causing internal bleeding.
并造成内出血
It does this by disturbing the delicate machinery
通过扰乱凝血的精密过程可以做到这些
of the blood coagulation system.
Venom can also be cytotoxic,
毒液也可能有细胞毒性
attacking cells, leading to severe blisters,
攻击细胞 产生严重的水泡
necrosis and cell death.
坏疽和细胞死亡
It can also be myotoxic,
它还可以有肌肉毒性
destroying muscles and causing paralysis.
摧毁肌肉并导致瘫痪
The worst part is that snake venoms
更糟糕的事情是
can contain up to 200 compounds.
蛇毒可包含高达 200 种化合物
Most venoms contain a combination of neurotoxic,
大多数毒液中含有多种毒性蛋白
hemotoxic, cytotoxic and myotoxic proteins.
能同时具有神经毒性、血液毒性、细胞毒性和肌肉毒性
This is what makes snake bites so difficult to treat.
因此蛇咬伤才如此难以治疗
It's not just one toxin you're trying to neutralize,
你不仅仅是需要中和一种毒素
but dozens all working together to try to kill you.
而是数十种试图一同杀死你的毒素
Come on.
过来吧
Good boy.
乖孩子
There we go.
好嘞
I've been at the park for 10 years this year.
这已经是我在这个公园的第 10 个年头了
I've been running this facility for 7 1/2, eight.
我在这处设施得有七年半……八年了吧
Have you ever been bitten?
你被咬过吗？
Yeah, so about 3 1/2 years ago, I got a scratch.
啊 有的 大约三年半之前 我被划伤了
One finger got nicked.
一根手指被划伤了
That was 36 hours in ICU
在重症监护待了 36 个小时
and eight of those were on a resus bay.
其中 8 小时是在抢救室
So very, very serious.
非常非常严重
And what was that experience like?
那是一种怎样的体验？
That was crappy.
那真是糟透了
As it turns out,
事实证明
I'm highly allergic to antivenom, which is not ideal.
我对抗蛇毒血清高度过敏 这可不是好事
I started swelling up looking like the Elephant Man.
我浑身肿胀 看起来好似“象人”
So then they whack you with adrenaline
他们接着给你打肾上腺素抵抗过敏反应
to cancel out the anaphylaxis
and then they have to give you more anti-venom,
然后他们必须给你打更多血清
more adrenaline, more anti-venom, more adrenaline,
更多肾上腺素 更多血清 更多肾上腺素
more anti-venom, more adrenaline.
更多血清 更多肾上腺素……
And thankfully, I only needed the one,
谢天谢地 我只需要第一剂
but it was like the best case scenario,
这应该是不幸中的万幸了
he didn't chew, he didn't bite,
蛇没有实际上咬到我
but literally just a scratch.
仅仅是划伤而已
So what is antivenom exactly?
那么抗蛇毒血清到底是什么
and how was it invented?
它又是如何被发明的
In 1870, a British military doctor, Edward Nicholson
1870年 一位英国军医爱德华·尼克森
was stationed in Burma,
在缅甸驻扎
and as he watched the local snake handlers,
他在观察当地的驯蛇师时
he noticed something strange.
注意到了一件奇怪的事
They would from time to time
驯蛇师偶尔会故意让眼镜蛇咬他们
deliberately get Cobras to bite them
in what he considered a form of tattooing.
他起初认为这是某种纹身
Nicholson reasoned that
他后来推断
they were intentionally exposing their bodies to the venom
驯蛇师是有意让自己的身体接触蛇毒
to develop an immune response.
来逐渐加强对蛇毒的免疫反应
He observed that the older snake handlers
他注意到年长的驯蛇师
were less affected by accidental bites
受到意外咬伤的影响
than the younger ones.
比年轻驯蛇师更小
So this dangerous practice seemed to be paying off.
所以这种危险的做法似乎很有效
20 years later in Saigon,
20 年后的越南西贡
a French medical researcher named
一位法国医学研究员
阿尔贝·卡尔梅特
was vaccinating local residents against smallpox.
在为当地居民接种天花疫苗
When he became aware of the threat posed by Cobras,
他在了解到眼镜蛇对人类的威胁之后
he wondered if it was possible
就想知道是否有可能
to make a vaccine for snake bites.
制出对抗蛇咬的疫苗
Back in Paris, he tried injecting rabbits
回到巴黎后  他尝试给兔子注射
with a tiny amount of Cobra venom
微量的眼镜蛇毒
starting with just .03 milligrams,
从 0.03 毫克开始
but each week, he injected the rabbits again
之后的每周他会继续给兔子注射
slowly increasing the dose.
并逐渐增加剂量
And after eight months of this,
在持续了 8 个月之后
the rabbits were receiving
兔子们每次注射
35 milligrams of Cobra venom at a time,
就要接受 35 毫克的眼镜蛇毒
that is 15 times the normal lethal dose in rabbits,
这是兔子正常情况下致死量的 15 倍
but they were still perfectly healthy.
但它们却仍然非常健康
The rabbits' immune systems had developed antibodies
兔子们的免疫系统产生了抗体
to neutralize the venom.
来中和蛇毒
So you can be vaccinated against snake bites
所以我们可以像对抗疾病那样
just as you can against disease,
接种抗蛇毒的疫苗
but who wants to be vaccinated
但谁又想接种所有种类的疫苗
against all different types of snakes
来对抗所有的蛇毒
just in case one bites you?
而仅仅就因为被一条蛇咬呢
It would be better, Calmette reasoned,
他推断 要是能在被咬之后
if you could administer antibodies after a bite.
能把抗体注射进去就好了
So he drew blood from a venom resistant rabbit
所以他抽出了抗蛇毒兔子的血
and isolated the serum which contains the antibodies,
将含有抗体的血清分离出来
and then he injected it into another rabbit
然后把血清注射给一只
that had never been exposed to venom.
从未接触过蛇毒的兔子
When he subsequently injected it
当他随后给这只兔子注射了
with twice the lethal dose of Cobra venom,
两倍致死量的眼睛蛇毒之后
the rabbit was just fine.
这只兔子毫发无伤
Immunity had been transferred from one rabbit to another.
对蛇毒的免疫力从一只兔子转移到了另一只兔子上
This was the first antivenom,
这就是世界上第一个抗蛇毒血清
or as the Frenchman, Calmette called it, antivenin,
或者 这位法国人叫它 Antivenin
which is why my phone always makes that auto-correction.
这是我手机键盘一直自动更正的原因吧
To this day, antivenoms are made in much the same way.
抗蛇毒血清的制作方法  一直以来变化不大
At the Reptile Park,
在爬行动物公园里
they collect and freeze the venom.
工作人员收集蛇毒并冷冻起来
It's sent off to be diluted
蛇毒被送去稀释
and injected into a donor animal, usually a horse.
然后被注射到一只供体动物体内 通常是马
Horses are used because of their size.
用马作供体动物  是因为马体型庞大
After increasing the dose over a period of months,
在数月内  逐渐增加注射的剂量之后
the horse builds up immunity to the venom,
马就会对这种蛇毒免疫
and then it's blood is drawn
然后人们把马的血抽出
and the antibodies are isolated.
从中分离出抗体
Only the plasma is taken,
提取时只取血浆
the red blood cells are returned to the horse.
红细胞会被注射回马体内
Those horse antibodies are the life saving antivenom.
这些马的抗体  就是能救命的抗蛇毒血清
Antivenom works for the same reason venom works,
抗蛇毒血清在人体内的工作机理  和蛇毒相似
because of our shared evolutionary history
因为我们和其他哺乳动物  有着共同的进化历史
with other mammals.
The antibodies produced by horses
马产生的抗体
are very similar to the ones produced by humans,
和人类产生的抗体非常相似
so they bind to toxic compounds and neutralize them
因此也能和毒素结合 并中和它们
even in our bodies.
哪怕是在人类体内
But this way of making antivenom has downsides.
但是这种制备抗蛇毒血清的方式也有缺点
Collecting the venom is dangerous,
收集蛇毒的过程非常危险
many donor animals are involved,
需要很多很多供体动物参与
and some people are allergic to antivenom.
而且有些人对抗蛇毒血清过敏
Scientists are now exploring the possibility
科学家正在探索另一种可能
of producing antivenom using genetically modified bacteria.
用修改过基因的细菌来生产抗蛇毒血清
They would produce the specific antibodies
这些细菌可以产生
needed to neutralize each toxin in a venom,
毒液中各个毒素的特异中和抗体
but for now, this is the way antivenom is made.
但现阶段只能利用供体生产抗蛇毒血清
How's your arm?
你胳膊感觉如何
Yeah, it's a bit sore.
还行 有点酸
The shoulder is a bit tender.
肩膀有点软了
The work Zac and others like him do
像 Zac 这些人所做的工作
saves countless lives all around the world.
可以拯救世界上无数的生命
If you're up here for fame and fortune,
如果你是为了名利而来
and oh, look how tough I am milking snakes,
就是为了装逼 “哇 看我取蛇毒多辛苦”
you don't last long.
你干不了多久的
You get chewed on and you go, oh, this is not for me.
你终究会被咬，然后说 “算了 我不适合干这个”
If you're up here because you love the animals
但如果你来这里  是因为热爱动物的话
and this is an opportunity
这是个好机会
to not only work with the animals you love,
能和你喜爱的动物接触
but to actively be a part of saving lives.
并积极参与拯救生命
Like I'm not smart enough to be a doctor,
比如  虽然我不够聪明  当不了医生
I'll put that out there straight away,
我不拐弯抹角
but I can swing a snake pretty good.
但我很善于摆弄这些蛇